<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
	version="5.0" xml:lang="en">

	<info>
		<title>Ephemeris</title>
	</info>
	<para>Ephemeris, defined as a diary or a journal with particular
		relation to the positions of heavenly bodies throughout the calendar
		year. The Ephemeris project explores our experience of time. It allows
		us to perceive time in a non-uniform way.
	</para>
	<para>The city has many time based events interwoven into everyday
		life. The events can be visualised as the time at which one leaves a
		source and the time one arrives at a destination. For instance leaving
		home at 8:45am to arriving at work at 8:59pm, or leaving the
		restaurant at 9:00pm and arriving at the bench by the waters edge at
		9:15pm.
	</para>
	<para>In the above examples, time was experienced on the same scale but
		in entirely different ways. Whilst the person rushing for work
		possibly did not notice or experience the fullness of that 15 minutes,
		the couple going for a romantic stroll possibly experienced this time
		as an eternity.
	</para>
	<para>The Ephemeris project is intended to provide control over our
		natural passage through time. It also provides us with the means to
		revisit lost time.
	</para>

	<section>
		<title>Ephemeris - About</title>
		<para>The theory of relativity states that each persons experience of
			time is different to anothers. Whilst a sprinter may experience the
			length of the track by concentrating on patterns of movement and
			positions of opponents, the audience will experience this entirely
			differently. To the audience, the race will be over almost as quickly
			as it started, whereas the sprinter may be able to recall every
			footstep. This difference in experience of time is found frequently,
			and has brought about the commonly used phrase &quot;Time flies when
			you're having fun&quot;.</para>
		<para>The Ephemeris project intends to make the passage of time
			controllable. It works by providing control of the speed of time in a
			shared environment.
		</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="uni/ephemeris/images/game1.jpg" />
			</imageobject>
			<textobject>
				<phrase>Screenshot of the Application</phrase>
			</textobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>When entering the Ephemeris environment, a cityscape is
			provided. A city is a place in which strangers are more common than
			friends. As such, it is possible to walk through the city without
			ever knowing others experiences of the same events. Whilst a lone
			person waiting for an event (such as waiting for a bus) may fully
			experience 5 minutes of time, an individual with a goal to reach an
			event (such as somebody rushing to get to work on time) may not
			concentrate on this same time and will therefore not experience it in
			the same way. The two individuals may well pass one another without
			realising they are both experiencing different time.
		</para>
		<para>In the same way, Ephemeris allows the visitor to experience time
			as though it were flying by. One minute lasts one second. Another
			visitor may be experiencing time as though they wished to see every
			moment. In this case one minute lasts an hour. Both visitors have the
			possibility to see one another, but both be in entirely different
			times.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Ephemeris - Details</title>
		<para>The Epehemeris project is created as a Java 3D applet. Upon
			entering Ephemeris, the visitor is assigned a timeline with the
			standard time equal to a clock in reality. All movements are logged
			as events in this timeline and are distributed to all others within
			Ephemeris.
		</para>
		<para>The visitor can then alter their present rate of time. This is
			equivalent to a percentage of the time of a clock in reality. So 50%
			of time will mean that 1 second in Ephemeris is worth 2 seconds in
			reality. To this visitor, everything else in Ephemeris will slow
			down. To a visitor who stays at 100% of time, the other will be at
			equal pace, and then speed up as soon as they changed to 50% of time.
		</para>
		<para>Because events are logged, it is also possible to experience
			yourself in Ephemeris. If you enter Ephemeris and change time to 200%
			of time, 1 second in Ephemeris will be equivalent to 1/2 second in
			reality. Therefore by remaining in Ephemeris for 20 minutes in
			reality, 40 minutes will have passed in Ephemeris. By then leaving
			and re-entering Epehemeris, you will see the ghost of yourself in
			Ephemeris' future.
		</para>
		<para>Attempting to explain Ephemeris is a lot harder than
			experiencing it for yourself. Please visit Ephemeris and experience
			time.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Ephemeris - Conclusions</title>
		<para>Currently the Ephemeris project successfully accomplishes the
			primary goal set out in the aims of the project. That is it
			successfully illustrates the experience of time and a change in time.
			Unfortunately this is only successfully illustrated by presenting the
			project with 2 machines running side by side.</para>
		<para>In order for the project to become useful as a wider distributed
			experience, other elements would be needed. Obvious points would be
			that the orbiting sun would reflect the current time and therefore
			orbit more quickly if time is being experienced at an increased rate.
			Also a chat facility in which visitors could type text and have those
			words appear above their character would help to illustrate the
			passages of time. Limitations such as time and technology prevented
			these features being added in this first release.</para>
		<para>The project does prove that as individuals we cannot be sure
			that we all do exist in the same time. The only way to prove one way
			or the other would be to interrupt everybody you pass and ask them
			what they think the time is. It also asks the question as to how much
			control we have over our passage through time. Is there any conscious
			decision to how quickly we perceive time? Ephemeris provides this
			control as an experiment to see how we might react.</para>
		<para>Initial visitors to Ephemeris are typically confused by what
			they see. It takes some time for them to realise what they are
			experiencing. However, in reality, they deal with the same experience
			subconsciously. By interacting with somebody, you must both match
			your pace through time.</para>
		<para>As a result, the conclusions lead me to believe that it is
			entirely possible that we all exist in different times. We then
			synchronize our times as we interact with others around us. And
			nobody's timeline through life is the same as anothers.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
