<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
	version="5.0" xml:lang="en">

	<info>
		<title>BitRot Media Player</title>
	</info>
	<para>BitRot Media Player is an application that translates the process
		of degradation from the actual to the virtual.
	</para>
	<imagedata fileref="images/bitrotsmall.jpg" />
	<para>Media such as vinyl and magnetic tape all had their flaws. By
		storing data in analogue form on analogue media, degradation begins to
		distort and fragment content. Digital media such as CD's are reputed
		to be free from degradation and decomposition. Digital data stored on
		impervious media. But is this completely true?
	</para>
	<para>The BitRot Media Player translates the process a vinyl record
		undergoes to the virtual space. Now, when video and audio is viewed
		and listened to, a certain amount of the original will be lost through
		degradation.
	</para>

	<section>
		<title>About the BitRot Media Player</title>
		<para>
			Here are 2 descriptions taken from The Jargon File (
			<ulink url="http://www.science.uva.nl/%7Emes/jargon/">
				http://www.science.uva.nl/~mes/jargon/
			</ulink>
			):
		</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>bit rot:</emphasis>
					n. [common] Also bit decay. Hypothetical disease the existence of
					which has been deduced from the observation that unused programs or
					features will often stop working after sufficient time has passed,
					even if `nothing has changed'. The theory explains that bits decay
					as if they were radioactive. As time passes, the contents of a file
					or the code in a program will become increasingly garbled.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>software rot:</emphasis>
					n. Term used to describe the tendency of software that has not been
					used in a while to lose; such failure may be semi-humorously
					ascribed to bit rot. More commonly, `software rot' strikes when a
					program's assumptions become out of date. If the design was
					insufficiently robust, this may cause it to fail in mysterious
					ways.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>I hoped to create a virtual illustration of one of two
			principles that only apply to the actual. Decay and degradation
			(supposedly) cannot occur in the virtual, as many failsafes built
			into hardware prevent such an occurence. However in the actual,
			apples rot, and VCR cassettes degrade.
		</para>
		<para>An apple can be used to represent the idea of decay. If left for
			a sufficient amount of time, an apple will begin to rot. It starts to
			lose whatever it was that made it an apple, until it no longer is an
			apple.
		</para>
		<para>A VCR Cassette has no idea of decay. It is made of plastics
			intended to make it durable, making its rate of decay greater than a
			life span. It does however degrade. Over time, wear and tear through
			its use will cause the VCR cassette to begin to lose the information
			it contains. Whilst the cassette will undoubtedly remain a cassette,
			the information it contains will ultimately (through use) degrade
			until it no longer exists.
		</para>
		<para>It is the process of degradation therefore that I am attempting
			to translate from the actual to the virtual. If in the virtual, by
			re-using the same area of a disk, degradation were to occur. The
			degradation would not be in the virtual representation of the file
			itself, but rather in the physical collection of 1's and 0's that
			make up the file. Through use, the 1's would be lost as electrical
			circuits failed and degraded. The BitRot Media Player mimics this
			behaviour as an illustration of the process.
		</para>
		<para>As a video is played in the BitRot Media Player, 1's are lost
			from the sequence of bits that make up the file. Technically the
			application measures the period of the file that is played, and runs
			the degradation process on that portion. Therefore, every time a part
			of a video is watched, it is also lost permanently.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Consequences Through use of the BitRot Media Player</title>
		<para>Using the BitRot Media Player as a replacement to the
			traditional Quicktime Movie Player will require a different outlook
			on how media is stored in the virtual space. Similar to how we treat
			VCR cassettes, the original of the media will need to be kept and
			never played, as a copy degrades through use. When authoring a VCR
			cassette, the master copy serves the same purpose.
		</para>
		<para>In this case, the translation of the principles and processes of
			degradation have been faithfully replicated in the BitRot Media
			Player. Where the player fails is in the principles of the virtual.
			In certain ways, the virtual is already a place of degradation. When
			creating a word processor document, the author is encouraged to keep
			a backup of the document. The reason typically is in case of a state
			of decay in the storage device. By keeping a backup copy on a
			seperate storage medium, a failsafe is created against any accidental
			corruption through decay of the originals storage device. More
			importantly though (in relation to BitRot Media Player), a backup is
			kept in case of degradation of the document through the author's
			error. The author can decide to revert to the backup copy of the
			document if they decide they preffered the older text to whatever
			they have just created. In a way, this is degredation of the quality
			and therefore content of the document.
		</para>
		<para>So how does this affect the BitRot Media Player? If the virtual
			already contains many states of decay, what purpose does the BitRot
			player have? Perhaps as an illustration and a reminder of the
			importance of degradation, the BitRot player serves a purpose.
		</para>
		<para>Interestingly, the BitRot player also displays design principles
			of virtual media in a very clear way. Quicktimes .mov and Microsoft's
			.avi file formats are incredibly sensitive to discrepancies in the
			structure of the file. The slightest amount of degradation can render
			the file unviewable. Media intended for distributed release, such as
			the MPEG's 'streaming' design structure allow .mpg's and .mp3's to be
			degraded to a substantially greater level before they become both
			noticeably poorer in quality or unplayable. This is an interesting
			design concept as MPEG is designed to withstand moderately intense
			degradation of its structure. This is perhaps an indication of an
			acknowledgement of degeradation in storage or transfer in the virtual
			space.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Download BitRot Media Player</title>
		<para>Unfortunately I haven't got a reliable install method for the
			compiled Media Player. I will attempt to have a compiled version
			ready by the end of June. The reason for this is that the BitRot
			Media Player requires that Quicktime and Quicktime for Java be
			installed. I just haven't found a reliable method of ensuring both
			are installed (in a cross platform way).</para>
		<para>
			The source code is available on
			<ulink url="https://github.com/KolonelKustard/bitrot-media-player">GitHub</ulink>.
			This code is given as is, and no licence or acceptance of blame etc
			for misuse is granted.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
