<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
	version="5.0" xml:lang="en">

	<info>
		<title>Free CGI-UK</title>
	</info>
	<para>Free CGI-UK is a hoax web site intended to entice Internet users
		to fill out its form. The site offers free CGI hosting for a variety
		of server side protocols. Once the user has filled in their details,
		they are added to the database and enlisted to take part in the Free
		CGI-UK project.
	</para>
	<imagedata fileref="images/screenshot1.gif" />
	<para>The project aims to attack current mis-conceptions of Free.
		Nothing is truely free. 2 for the price of 1 inevitably means another
		item becomes more expensive. Free web space means forced advertising.
		The list goes on.
	</para>
	<para>Free is simply a marketing tool used to entice customers into
		inadvertently spending money.
	</para>
	<para>So when a user signs up for Free CGI-UK, why should anything be
		any different? Free CGI-UK need to make money too...
	</para>

	<section>
		<title>Free CGI-UK - About</title>
		<para>The idea of exchange has been the foundation for modern
			economics. In a modern state run market based economy, currency is
			exchanged for goods or services. The state is then responsible for
			managing the market and ensuring fair trading and lawfulness. The
			Internet, because of its global nature, has no governing body.
			Therefore there is no inherent protection of property rights. On the
			Internet, otherwise lawful people lose any sense of lawfulness.
			Hobbyists who would have no intentions of robbing a bank in
			actuality, are quite prepared to hack into a bank in virtuality. This
			has led to any traders in the Internet being responsible for their
			own security, and their own protection of property. This has shaped
			the modern web server.
		</para>
		<para>The web server can be likened to a medieval fortress. Security
			quite often is the most important feature of a web server, overriding
			speed and efficiency. Users of the Internet are only ever permitted
			to view a tiny proportion of a web server, similar to the fortress
			having an open market. Only the permitted privileged few can have
			further levels of access, depending on either their status, or how
			much they are willing to exchange. This limits the inhabitants of a
			fortress to friends and family of the owner, and the wealthy. In the
			case of the web server, this is employees and the paying customer.
		</para>
		<para>Web hosting companies find it difficult to make money in
			virtuality. This is because there is no tangible property in virtual
			space, and therefore no sense of value.
		</para>
		<para>In order for web hosting companies to make money, the majority
			will rely on aspects of actuality. This could be offering free web
			hosting, but forcing advertising onto users. Or offering free web
			hosting as long as users dial up through a particular account. In
			order for web hosting companies to gain paying customers they often
			resort to offering the hosting for free and getting money from
			customers in other means. The number of 'free' web hosting companies
			offering greater and greater privileges, but with more and more
			catches, is phenomenal.
		</para>
		<para>I would argue that all users in virtuality have the right to
			freedom with no repercussions. A visitor to virtuality is escaping
			actuality, and as such should be removed entirely from any direct
			links to actuality. Because of this, I have decided to base my
			project on perverting the existing free systems.
		</para>
		<para>I have created a hoax web hosting company that are offering
			users massive privileges for their web sites. The company (Free CGI
			UK - www.freecgiuk.co.uk) will in turn be expecting something back
			from their users. The automated Free CGI UK server does this in a
			number of ways.
		</para>
		<para>Firstly, the user will be phoned and asked to make an
			appointment for a representative of Free CGI UK to visit. Once they
			have done this, a letter of confirmation will be posted and e-mail
			sent. Free CGI UK will need to do this, as the users property will
			become their method of payment.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section xml:id="application">
		<title>Free CGI-UK - Application</title>
		<para>The execution of this project has been limited to just the
			registering and phone calling elements. I left out the e-mailed
			responses and letters of confirmation to concentrate my time on the
			telephone application.
		</para>
		<para>
			<link linkend="theSite">The web site</link>
			is the method of registration. A user visits the Free CGI UK web site
			and registers their interest for the service, filling in address and
			phone number.
		</para>
		<imagedata fileref="images/screenshot1.gif" />
		<para>These details are then added to a database and used later by the
			telephone application.
		</para>
		<para>The telephone application takes the list of users, and
			sequentially phones them up, one after the other. The user answers
			the phone, and is greeted by the machine saying:
		</para>
		<para>
			"Hello
			<emphasis>*users name*</emphasis>
			from Free CGI UK. Thank you for registering with us. We are very
			grateful for your interest. In order for your application to be
			completed we will need to evaluate your property. When would be a
			suitable time for one of our representatives to visit?"
		</para>
		<para>The machine will then listen for a response, record the resonse,
			and reply with the following:
		</para>
		<para>
			"Thank you from Free C G I UK. We will be in contact with you
			regarding your appointment for
			<emphasis>*users response*</emphasis>
			. Is there anything you would like to ask me regarding Free C G I
			UK?"
		</para>
		<para>Following this, it will then have a conversation with the user
			until the allotted 2 minute maximum call length is reached, after
			which it will say goodbye and hang up.
		</para>
		<para>This process is entirely automated using a combination of voice
			modem management, speech recognition, text to speech and the ALICE
			chat bot.
		</para>
		<para>The application is installed using 2 computers. One PC runs the
			phone management application using the Microsoft JDK (Java
			Development Kit) with the Microsoft TAPI (Telephony Application
			Programming Interface) version 3 for Windows 2000. Another PC uses
			the communications application which runs the Sun JDK using the Chant
			SpeechKit 2.1.2 which implements an interface to the Microsoft SAPI
			(Speech Application Programming Interface) version 4. This
			application also runs the ALICE chat bot version b for Java.
		</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/phoneappbig.jpg" format="JPG" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The phone app</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/commappbig.jpg" format="JPG" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The Communications App</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>The applications are very difficult to set up and run. They
			require 2 TCP/IP networked IBM compatible PC's. The phone app
			requires Windows 2000, and the communications app requires any
			Windows 95+ or Windows NT4+ platform. The 2 machines must be linked
			together with a pair of audio cables too. This is from the speaker
			out to the line in of both machines.
		</para>
		<para>If the applications are installed successfully, they will run
			through the list of users automatically, requiring no supervision.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section xml:id="results">
		<title>Free CGI-UK - Results</title>
		<para>During the time the Free CGI UK web site was online, a number of
			users did register for the service. These users were then phoned.
			Here is some example dialog from the phone calls:
		</para>
		<segmentedlist>
			<segtitle>FCGI</segtitle>
			<segtitle>User</segtitle>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>You must be very intelligent.</seg>
				<seg>Yes. Yes. I suppose so.</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>You sound very excited.</seg>
				<seg>Hahaha</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>I'm glad I amuse you.</seg>
			</seglistitem>
		</segmentedlist>
		<para>
			To read part of the applications automatically generated log, see
			<xref linkend="appLog" />.
		</para>
		<para>The running of this application was very successful. However,
			the quality of recorded matter was very poor due to the poor quality
			of components making up the 2 PC's. The modem and sound cards
			produced a lot of background noise, making the text to speech
			difficult for users to follow.
		</para>
		<para>
			To hear any of the clips, download the relevant .mp3 file from the
			<xref linkend="downloads" /> section.
		</para>
		<para>The audio clip 1 is a typical conversation with an unsuspecting
			user. This user had no idea that they would be phoned, and as such
			hung up! The more interesting results came from the users who were
			expecting to be phoned (my friends!). The audio clip 2 is a
			particularly good example of this.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Free CGI-UK - Conclusions</title>
		<para>Technically, a lot more work was needed in refining the
			applications. Dedicated telephony equipment would have greatly
			improved quality and efficiency.
		</para>
		<para>I hope the project served its purpose. I don't actually think
			any
			of the users telephoned for the cause can have had a clue what was
			going on, however hopefully the confusion will worry them into being
			a
			little more careful as to what they sign up for now though. Maybe I
			will follow the calls up and get some opinions. Although I feel the
			event will be long forgotten.
		</para>
		<para>It is interesting to see that big companies with huge call
			centres are still relying on push button telephone operated menu
			systems for their calls. The idea of press '1' for this, press '2'
			for
			that now seems to be a little dated. Would it not be possible for a
			machine to ask what the call is about, and make an calculated guess
			from the response?
		</para>
		<para>It would also seem that the technology for speech recognition is
			still in its infancy. The trouble is with training. Most speech
			recognition systems use training to learn vocabularies from their
			user. This training can take some time. With a phone call, a
			different
			person is greeted each time, each with their own vocabulary and
			accent.
		</para>
		<para>The most concerning aspect from this project is the ability to
			abuse. This project is designed to abuse rights, to provoke thinking
			about what is free. However it would be just as simple to abuse this
			technology to have automated double-glazing sales people and
			automated
			market surveys.
		</para>
		<para>
			Overall I am very satisfied with this project. I have achieved all I
			had hoped to achieve, and now have some amusing results to listen to.
			I hope the flow of 'free' services on the Internet slows down a
			little, as it may end up giving bad press for truly free services
			such as at GNU (GNU's Not Unix - see the links page), which are the
			true foundation of the Internet community.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section xml:id="downloads">
		<title>Free CGI-UK - Download</title>
		<para>
			The downloads are split into the
			<link linkend="apps">downloadable applications</link>
			with source, and some
			<link linkend="sounds">sound clips</link>
			from the running of the applications.
		</para>
		<section xml:id="apps">
			<title>Applications</title>
			<para>It is important to note that in developing the app, I have used
				every shortcut under the sun. The app is very much machine specific,
				and I warn you that you will have NO luck in simply installing and
				running them. They are potentially only useful for developers to
				download, maybe to see how I've hacked about with the various
				components.</para>
			<para>
				<ulink url="https://github.com/KolonelKustard/freecgiuk/releases/" />
			</para>
			<para>
				The phone manager needs to be run in Windows 2000 using the
				Microsoft JDK and TAPI3. Visit the
				<ulink url="http://msdn.microsoft.com">MSDN web site</ulink>
				to download both of these.
			</para>
			<para>
				The Communicator uses a modified version of the ALICE chat bot, and
				also uses the Chant SpeechKit 2.1.2. You will need to download the
				speechkit from here:
				<ulink url="http://www.speechkit.com" />
				to run this.
			</para>
			<para>
				You will need to download the Alice chat bot and modify it or my
				code to use it with this app. I couldn't include it with this
				download because it's too big. Download version b of Alice from
				<ulink url="http://www.alicebot.org/" />
			</para>
			<para>There is also currently no database of users included. The code
				uses JDBC though, so simply use your own!</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="sounds">
			<title>Example Results</title>
			<para>The first audio file is from an unsuspecting user. The second
				audio file is from a user who was expecting to be phoned:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<ulink url="http://kolonelkustard.github.io/freecgiuk/audioclip1.wav">audioclip1.wav</ulink>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<ulink url="http://kolonelkustard.github.io/freecgiuk/audioclip2.wav">audioclip2.wav</ulink>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section xml:id="theSite">
		<title>Free CGI-UK - The Site</title>
		<para>
			The live site is no more but there is an archive of the site here:
			<ulink url="http://kolonelkustard.github.io/freecgiuk/thesite/" />
		</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Free CGI-UK - Technology</title>
		<para>
			So what is the technology behind making the automated phone caller of
			Free CGI UK? The application is split into two seperate components,
			as can be seen by visiting the
			<link linkend="application">application</link>
			page. I will now break down what they do and why I have chosen
			particular paths.
		</para>
		<section>
			<title>Phone Manager</title>
			<para>
				The phone manager is a
				<emphasis>fairly</emphasis>
				simple component. I chose to use the Microsoft TAPI (Telephony
				Application Programming Interface) to interface with the voice modem
				in my PC. I would have used Sun's JTAPI (Java TAPI), but as yet
				there are no free implementations.
			</para>
			<para>Because I have very little knowledge of C++, I had to then
				limit myself to using the TAPI 3.0 which ships with Windows 2000,
				which uses the Microsoft COM model, and is therefore compatible with
				the Microsoft Java SDK and its handy non-Sun-friendly JActiveX (Sun
				are currently trying to quash this feature as it goes against the
				machine independance principles of Java!).</para>
			<para>So the phone app uses a heavily butchered example class from
				Microsoft, which is called from a management app, which also handles
				a network connection to the communications component running on
				another PC. The communications component then instructs the phone
				manager on what to dial, when to change the direction of the audio,
				and when to disconnect.</para>
			<para>The MAJOR limitation currently with the phone manager is with
				my machine. I unfortunately have an ancient modem with no native
				TAPI drivers. It is therefore managed by the Microsoft Unimodem/V
				default drivers. This unfortunately means the modem does not support
				full-duplex, and as such, when the direction of audio needs to be
				changed, a pause of anywhere between 1 to 10 seconds can occur as
				one stream is stopped, and another started.</para>
			<para>
				Ideally I would have gone out and bought a decent
				<ulink url="http://www.dialogic.com">Dialogic</ulink>
				modem and used the JTAPI implementation they supply. But
				unfortunately I'm a student...!
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Communicator</title>
			<para>The communicator is a little more complicated than the phone
				manager!!! It is an entirely automated component of the entire
				application, requiring one or two selections from the user with
				regards to selecting speech engines prior to running.</para>
			<para>Firstly I will run through the order in which tasks happen,
				then I will expand upon some of the points.</para>
			<para>On starting the application, it will ask for the IP of the
				machine running the phone manager. If it successfully connects to
				the phone manager, it will then begin initialisation.</para>
			<para>It preloads the vocabularies of the ALICE bot, then asks the
				user to select a speech recognition engine, then asks the user to
				select a text-to-speech engine. The speech engines are then
				initialised. Finally the users details are read from the databse
				into memory.</para>
			<para>Once initialisation has completed, the main program loop
				begins. Each loop constructs a new phone call with a 2 minute
				maximum length, following a short structured dialogue, and an
				attempt to converse using the ALICE bot.</para>
			<para>Once a user has either hung up, or the 2 minutes maximum call
				length is reached, the communications app will instruct the phone
				manager to disconnect the current call and begin the next call.
			</para>
			<para>This continues until all the users in the database have been
				phoned.</para>
			<para>
				To hear some conversations recorded using the application, visit the
				<xref linkend="results" />
				section or the
				<xref linkend="downloads" />
				section.
			</para>
			<para>
				I will now delve a little deeper into the Communicator application.
				It runs using the ALICE bot (
				<ulink url="http://www.alicebot.org/" />) for AI chatting, and
				the Chant Speechkit 2.1.2 (
				<ulink url="http://www.speechkit.com" />) for speech recognition
				and text-to-speech. The Chant speechkit
				provides an interface to an variety of speech engines. I chose the
				Microsoft SAPI 4.0 as it was free! I was going to use the SAPI 5.0,
				as it now implements the COM object model. However I didn't have
				time to hack around with it, and there is currently no direct
				support for Java developers.
			</para>
			<para>When a call is created, the phone manager returns a connected
				message. The communicator must then decipher between the noises of a
				phone ringing and the noise of somebody's voice as they answer the
				phone. This is because the noise of a phone ringing created when you
				phone another line is provided by the telephony provider you dial
				to. This gives the impression of a call being connected even though
				it is not. Therefore, the speech recognition has a list of phrases
				to ignore when listening for an answer. The list of phrases I
				created are:</para>
			<para>"it's a", "hurt", "good who", "coup", "aha", "a", "they", "they
				they", "a. a.", "a good", "good a", "good good", "to", "to to", "a
				a", "and", "and and", "a new", "new new"</para>
			<para>This is quite interesting in itself, as this is what the speech
				recognition recognised to be ringing tones!</para>
			<para>
				To see exactly how it all works, download the app from the
				<xref linkend="downloads" /> section.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	
	<section xml:id="appLog">
		<title>Application log</title>
		
		<segmentedlist>
			<title>23/01/2001 20:10:34</title>
			<segtitle>FCGI</segtitle>
			<segtitle>User</segtitle>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Hello Mr Ben Wakeford from Free CGI UK. Thank you for
                  registering with us. We are very grateful for your interest.
                  In order for your application to be completed we will need to
                  evaluate your property. When would be a suitable time for one
                  of our representatives to visit?</seg>
				<seg>tomorrow</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Thank you from Free C G I UK. We will be in contact
                  with you regarding your appointment for tomorrow. Is there anything
                  you would like to ask me regarding Free C G I UK?</seg>
				<seg>no web site</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Would you ever do it?</seg>
				<seg>pardon</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>You're excused</seg>
				<seg>don't understand unfamiliar</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Oh I'm sorry. Perhaps I can explain it again better.</seg>
				<seg>yes</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Perhaps I can explain it again better. Yes?</seg>
				<seg>yes definately</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>What makes you so certain?</seg>
				<seg>part properly</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>What part are you confused about?</seg>
				<seg>part questions</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Would you like to have it?</seg>
				<seg>Have what?</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Questions</seg>
				<seg>no thankyou</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>You are quite welcome.</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Right I'm off now. Thanks for your time.</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
		</segmentedlist>
		
		<segmentedlist>
			<title>23/01/2001 20:14:04</title>
			<segtitle>FCGI</segtitle>
			<segtitle>User</segtitle>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Hello Mr Johan Ribenfors from Free CGI UK. Thank you
                  for registering with us. We are very grateful for your interest.
                  In order for your application to be completed we will need to
                  evaluate your property. When would be a suitable time for one
                  of our representatives to visit?</seg>
				<seg>hello</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Thank you from Free C G I UK. We will be in contact
                  with you regarding your appointment for hello. Is there anything
                  you would like to ask me regarding Free C G I UK?</seg>
				<seg>no</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>OK</seg>
				<seg>hello</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Hi there.</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Right I'm off now. Thanks for your time.</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
		</segmentedlist>
		
		<segmentedlist>
			<title>23/01/2001 20:15:40</title>
			<segtitle>FCGI</segtitle>
			<segtitle>User</segtitle>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Hello Mr Simon Wainwright from Free CGI UK. Thank you
                  for registering with us. We are very grateful for your interest.
                  In order for your application to be completed we will need to
                  evaluate your property. When would be a suitable time for one
                  of our representatives to visit?</seg>
				<seg>anytime fine</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Thank you from Free C G I UK. We will be in contact
                  with you regarding your appointment for anytime fine. Is there
                  anything you would like to ask me regarding Free C G I UK?</seg>
				<seg>no I know everything</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>You must be very intelligent.</seg>
				<seg>yes</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Yeah that's right. You sound excited.</seg>
				<seg>ha ha</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>I'm glad you got a laugh out of it.</seg>
				<seg>main</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Thanks for explaining it.</seg>
				<seg>problem</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Try asking me something else.</seg>
				<seg>hello</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Hi there</seg>
				<seg>how doing</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>I'm doing great. How about you?</seg>
				<seg>tired fine</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Maybe you should get some rest.</seg>
				<seg>good dear</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Thanks for the compliment. Quite honestly I wouldn't
                  worry myself about that.</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Right I'm off now. Thanks for your time.</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
		</segmentedlist>
		    
		<segmentedlist>
			<title>23/01/2001 20:18:02</title>
			<segtitle>FCGI</segtitle>
			<segtitle>User</segtitle>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Hello Mr Justin Rosewell from Free CGI UK. Thank you
                  for registering with us. We are very grateful for your interest.
                  In order for your application to be completed we will need to
                  evaluate your property. When would be a suitable time for one
                  of our representatives to visit?</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Thank you from Free C G I UK. We will be in contact
                  with you regarding your appointment for . Is there anything
                  you would like to ask me regarding Free C G I UK?</seg>
				<seg>hello</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Hi there</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Right I'm off now. Thanks for your time.</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
		</segmentedlist>
		
		<segmentedlist>
			<title>23/01/2001 20:19:12</title>
			<segtitle>FCGI</segtitle>
			<segtitle>User</segtitle>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Hello Miss Jo Miller from Free CGI UK. Thank you for
                  registering with us. We are very grateful for your interest.
                  In order for your application to be completed we will need to
                  evaluate your property. When would be a suitable time for one
                  of our representatives to visit?</seg>
				<seg>anytime ralph</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Thank you from Free C G I UK. We will be in contact
                  with you regarding your appointment for anytime ralph. Is there
                  anything you would like to ask me regarding Free C G I UK?</seg>
				<seg>no</seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>I see</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
			<seglistitem>
				<seg>Right I'm off now. Thanks for your time.</seg>
				<seg></seg>
			</seglistitem>
		</segmentedlist>
	</section>
</chapter>
